okay so let us say that this is our OB
here this is a register allocation table
and this is our set of registers and
let's suppose that our instructions are
R 1 equals R 2 plus R 3 R 3 equals R 5 +
r 6 R 1 equals Rob 1 times R 7 it's Rob
1 here because we were really using R 1
and in got renamed this way and then R 1
equals R 4 plus R 8 and then R 2 equals
R 9 plus Rob - because it was really
using our 3 but it got renamed this way
let's say that all of these instructions
have finished and put the results in the
Rob and now it's time to commit them and
this is the next instruction that will
be committing at that point the rat
entries are gonna be for R 1 we need to
point to Rob for why well because the
entry in Rob 4 is the latest right to R
1 as far as the instructions that we
have issued is concerned so you know
this was pointing to the register and
then when this one was renamed it made
to point to Rob one and then when this
one was renamed we made that right entry
point to rob 3 and finally it became Rob
4 when this one was renamed and after
that we didn't rename any R 1
instructions are to the latest rename -
it was Rob 5 and then for R 3 the latest
rename of it was Rob - so this is what
we have in our rat for now and let's
assume that there are some values in the
registers here they don't matter anymore
because they will all be overwritten so
if you remember before we had the arrow
be when we were only doing tomasulo's
algorithm and were finishing
instructions out of order with no commit
at the end what was happening is as the
result is broadcast we needed to see
what's in the rat for that result and if
it says for example that this was
supposed to be produced by our
instruction meaning we were the latest
rename of this then we would update the
register file if for example the are one
entry said that it shouldn't be us that
broadcast the latest result then we
don't update the registers with the
arrow B this change is because now we
have the commit we will commit
instructions in the correct order in
order of program execution and each time
we commit an instruction we will deposit
its result in the registers no matter
what there
really says about it so when we commit
robbed one entry we're going to take
this result of our troop plus r3
whatever that value is and we will put
that value in the registers even though
the renaming in the rat says that this
is not the latest value for this
register however we are then gonna check
whether we are the latest rename and if
we are not then we are not going to
change the rat basically the the rat
needs to indicate that the latest
renamed value for R 1 is still Rob for
the fact that we have committed Rob 1
doesn't change that so after doing this
we free this Rob entry and it is now
ready to take another instruction now we
go to try to commit Rob to well again it
needs to write the result in r3 we take
the result of the instruction and we do
write it to the registers regardless of
what the rat says about it but then we
look at the right entry for r3 and check
whether the right entry says that we are
the latest rename for this value and in
this case we are so when we are
committing this instruction if the rat
keeps pointing at Rob 2 it's going to be
pointing at an empty entry that will
soon be used by some other instructions
so what we need to do is change the rat
to now point back to the registers for
r3 so we made the rat just point to the
r3 value in the registers no longer so
basically now if any instruction wants
to access r3 when it wants to read
operands it actually needs to get this
value not a value from the Rob and after
we have done this we can commit this
instruction fully which frees this side
of the entry and then we continue doing
this this instruction is the next one
that we will be committing so what we do
is we take this result we put it in our
one so we overwrite what was in our one
before we write whatever this value is
we then check whether for our one we are
the latest rename and we are not we are
up three this is Rob 4 so we leave the
rat entry alone and we can just free
this entry from the Rob now is a good
time to kind of stop and figure out you
know why are we doing this why are we
depositing values in the register that
we know are going to be over
and so on well we are doing it because
at any given point in time if we need to
stop there and take an exception like
for example now if we want to take an
exception what will happen is we can
just drain the Rob just just delete
everything that is still in there we can
make the entire rat just point to the
registers meaning we will just change
this entry to point to R 1 R 2 R 3 and
the content that we already have now in
the register file is exactly the content
as of this point so if we were not
updating the registers for every
instruction then we would not be able to
do this the registers would not be
up-to-date at this point and we would
not be able to take an exception by just
clearing everything from the rat and Rob
the fact that we did update it gives us
the ability to do this pretty much the
registers are always up-to-date as of
the commit point which means at any
given time we can just stop at that
point cancel everything from here make
this just point directly to the register
file and at that point we are ready to
fetch instructions from the exception
handler now let's say that that doesn't
happen what we can do then is just let's
commit these instructions just to kind
of illustrate once more what happens so
R 1 equals R 4 plus R 8 is our next
thing to commit we write that 2 R 1 of
writing this value we check whether we
are the latest training for R 1 we are
so we made the rat entry point directly
to R 1 basically from now on if somebody
wants to read R 1 they will end up
reading this not some Rob entry and now
we are ready to fully free this Rob
entry and finally we can commit this by
again writing this result checking
whether we are the latest rename yes we
are we point then directly to R 1 and we
finally freed this Arabi entry and if we
no longer have any instructions in the
Rob then we have a state exactly as it
should look when we have no instructions
in the Rob meaning the entire rat is
pointing directly to the registers the
registers are all up to date as of what
was committed latest and so on when you
are doing this be mindful of the fact
again that the values are copied to
registers as we commit regardless of
what the rat says but the rat is updated
on commit only if we are actually
changing the renaming from our Rob entry
to the registers if the renaming in the
rat is saying something else like some
other Rob entries still being pointed to
here then we leave it alone because the
rat needs to continue to point to the
latest value wherever that is